CURRICULUM VITAE



SULAIMAN SANKOH

Nationality: Sierra Leone

Phone number: (+232) 75977410

Email address: sankohsulaiman86@gmail.com

💡 Regent Road, Kamayama Lumley, Freetown, Sierra Leone

ABOUT ME

Highly experienced and visionary educationist with over 10 years of experience from within Sierra Leone and internationally. The ability to plan strategically, strong leadership, a strong work ethic and excellent communication skills empower me with the necessary components needed to achieve my mission of providing an excellent internationally recognized education that provides the very best opportunities for the young people to develop, grow and achieve academically.

I strive to create a productive and challenging environment where students are encouraged to learn, work, self reflect and aspire to consistently achieve the highest standards across all levels.

RESEARCH INTERESTS: Public governance, Institutional analysis and Public policy, Public Administration

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2021-2023 Master of Education (MED) in Educational Administration

Institution Niala University, Freetown, Sierra Leone

Thesis Title The Effect of Women's Education on Infant Mortality in Hamilton, Western Rural

2016-2018 Master of Science (MSc) in International Relations

Institution Shandong University, Jinan City, People's Republic of China

Thesis Title The Role of ECOWAS and International Organizations in Security Governance in West

Africa

2011-2014 Bachelor Degree Major in History/Politics)
Institution Fourah Bay College, University of Sierra Leone

2009-2011 Diploma in Adult Education and Community Studies)Institution Fourah Bay College, University of Sierra Leone

PUBLICATIONS

International Journal: The Role of Human Resource Officer in an Organization. Published 2022
International Journal: The Role of ECOWAS in Security Governance in West Africa. Published 2018

BOOK/Thesis: Author of: The Role of ECOWAS and International Organizations in Security Governance in West

Africa,

BOOK/Thesis: Author of: The Effect of Women's Education on Infant Mortality in Hamilton, Western Rural

District, Sierra Leone

AWARDS AND HONORS

Certificate of Publication, **February 2022**, International Journal Certificate of Honor, **July 2017**, Shandong University China Certificate of Publication, **July 2018**, International Journal for Social Studies

WORK EXPERIENCE

An Employee: Ministry of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation 2014 to date

Part Time Lecturer: Faulty of Leadership and Governance 2018 to present

Institute of Public Administration and Management, (IPAM), University of Sierra Leone

Chief Examiner: The West African Examinations Council (WAEC), January 2019- to present

DUTY •To attend coordination meetings prior to the commencement of marking exercise.

•To discuss and finalise a detailed scheme and to ensure that examiners maintain a uniform standard of marking throughout the marking period

Principal: Donnetteva Academy Senior Secondary School, Freetown, 2019 to 2022

DUTY

- Looking after the welfare and academic process of pupils.
- Coordinating and offering guidance and counselling services to the pupils
- In charge of class attendance and set standards of behaviour in school

• Ensure that there is availability of teaching materials, especially chalk and supervise

Supervisor: Statistic Sierra Leone, 2015 National Population and Housing Census

DUTY

- •Supervising the conducts of the 2015 National Population and Housing Census
- •Providing leadership to the enumerators in the exercise of the Census

Manager: International Students' Apartment Assistant, 2016-2018 Shandong University China

RECOMMENDATIONS

Professor Salamatu Binta

Position: Dean Faculty of Leadership and Governance

Institution: Institute of Public Administration and Management, University of Sierra Leone **Phone**

number: (+232) 76780314

Email: salamatubinta23@gmail.com

Dr. Abdul Karim Bangura

Position: Director of Diplomacy

Institution: Ministry of Foreign Affairs and International Cooperation

Phone number: (+232) 80032094 Email: karimbangs@gmail.com

Professor Abdulai Gbaratay Position: Senior Lecturer

Institution: Faculty of Political Science, Fourah Bay College, University of Sierra Leone

Phone number:

(+232) 88917616 Email: prof.abdulaigbaratay56@gmail.com